Ted Koppel Collection
Ted Koppel Collection
- The Koppel Report, 1988-1990
  - Death of a Dictator, aired 04/02/1990
    - Lenin Statue/Interview with Builders/Interview with Mayor of Bucharest/General Nicolae Cerbu Making Statement at Listening Post. (73) (Rupen No. B9), 03/04/1990; Lenin statue in Bucharest. Daytime. In square, Koppel interviews newly appointed mayor of Bucharest regarding the decision and the logistics involved in removing the statue. Koppel interview with unidentified man. General Cerbu makes a statement at telecommunications listening post, explaining the function of the listening post and describing the scope of its focus on monitoring military and diplomatic communications.; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:19:03; koppel_00071 (Box 3)
    - Lenin Statue/Stakeout (74) (Ron No. B9), 03/04/1990; Daytime. Crane operator securing cables at Lenin's head. Crowd watches demolition work from the square. Military officers survey the scene. After dark, welders working at the base of the statue; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:12:59; koppel_00072 (Box 3)
    - Major General Nicolae Cerbu Interview Part 1/Securitate Listening Post (75) (Rupen No. B10), 03/04/1990; Ted Koppel interview with Major General Nicolae Cerbu inside Securitate telecommunications listening center [Romanian with Engish translation] General Cerbu demonstrates the listening equipment and describes how the technical operation works. Cerbu describes the disabling of the listening apparatus and answers questions about the future of government surveillance in Romania. Video includes exterior b-roll footage of listening center; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:19:35; koppel_00073 (Box 3)
    - Lenin Statue Moves (76) (Ron No. B10), 03/05/1990; Daytime. Workers at base of Lenin statue. View of pedestrians in square. Crane lifts Lenin statue from podium as crowd cheers. Statue is lowered onto flatbed truck for removal; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:20:04; koppel_00074 (Box 3)
    - Major General Nicolae Cerbu Part 2/Securitate Listening Post (77) (Rupen No. B11), 03/04/1990; Ted Koppel interview with Major General Nicolae Cerbu inside Securitate telecommunications listening center [Romanian with Engish translation] Cerbu answers questions about the extent and quality of electronic surveillance in Romania under Ceausescu. Video concludes with interior b-roll footage of listening center, including detail views of listening equipment and electronics; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:21:11; koppel_00075 (Box 3)
    - Lenin Statue Driving Away (78) (Ron No. B11), 03/05/1990; Daytime. Lenin statue is removed from square on flatbed truck. Crowd in square watches; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:02:19; koppel_00076 (Box 3)
    - Listening Post Stand-Ups/Footage of Exteriors and Interiors at Snagov (79) (Rupen No. B12), 03/04/1990; Interior b-roll footage of listening center, including detail views of listening equipment and electronics. Ted Koppel stand-ups inside listening center (multiple takes). Exterior and interior footage of the Snagov presidential palace, including Nicolae Ceausescu's office; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:21:14; koppel_00077 (Box 3)
    - Snagov Interiors/Sergeant Major Enacme Lalescu Interview Part 1 (80) (Rupen No. B13), 03/04/1990; Exterior and interior footage of the Snagov presidential palace, including Nicolae Ceausescu's office and living quaraters. Ted Koppel interviews Sergean Major Enacme Lalescu, a military guard at the Snagov palace [Romanian with English translation] Lalescu describes the activities of Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu at the palace on the day of their attempted escape (22 Dec 1989); Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:20:59; koppel_00078 (Box 3)
    - Snagov Interiors/Bunker/Sergeant Major Enacme Lalescu Interview Part 2 (81) (Rupen No. B14), 03/04/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Sergeant Major Enacme Lalescu, a military guard at the Snagov palace [Romanian with English translation] Lalescu describes the activities of Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu at the palace on the day of their attempted escape (22 Dec 1989). Interior footage of the Snagov presidential palace, including indoor pool, statue and subterranean bunker; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:08:08; koppel_00079 (Box 3)
    - Colonel Vasile Malutan Interview Part 1 (82) (Rupen No. B15)., 03/05/1990; Footage of Lenin statue in Bucharest. Ted Koppel interviews Colonel Vasile Malutan, the individual who piloted the helicopter that Nicolae Ceausescu used to flee the Central Committee [in English] Malutan describes the landing, the takeoff, and the events that transpired in the air.; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:24:10; koppel_00080 (Box 3)
    - Colonel Vasile Malutan Interview Part 2 (83) (Rupen No. B16)., 03/05/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Colonel Vasile Malutan, the individual who piloted the helicopter that Nicolae Ceausescu used to flee the Central Committee Building [in English] Malutan describes the events that happened after Ceausescu departure from Snagov; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:21:13; koppel_00081 (Box 3)
    - Colonel Vasile Malutan Interview Part 3/Walking Shots on Roof/Tunnel Stand-Up (84) (Rupen No. B17), 03/05/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Colonel Vasile Malutan, the individual who piloted the helicopter that Nicolae Ceausescu used to flee the Central Committee Building [in English] Malutan discusses his role during the revolution. Footage of cityscape from roof. Walking shots of Koppel and Malutan. Point of view walking shots on roof. Ted Koppel standup inside tunnel system underneath the Central Committee Building.; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:19:55; koppel_00082 (Box 3)
    - Tunnel Stand-Ups/Interview with Army Colonel in Tunnel/Balcony Stand-Ups (85) (Rupen No. B18), 03/05/1990; Ted Koppel stand-ups inside tunnel system underneath the Central Committee Building (multiple takes). Interview with Army Colonel in tunnel system [in English] Koppel attempts to extract information about additional levels within the tunnels, but the Colonel denies there existence. Ted Koppel stand-ups on the balcony of the Central Committee Building (multiple takes).; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:20:38; koppel_00083 (Box 3)
    - Ted Koppel Goodnight Stand-Up/Statue of Dr. Petru Groza with Hunger Striking Cleric and Scaffolding/Old and New Poor Housing (86) (Rupen No. B19), 03/06/1990; Ted Koppel goodnight stand-up on a sidewalk (multiple takes). Vandalized statue of Dr. Petru Groza with crowds surrounding the monument along with a hunger striking cleric. Scenes of individuals placing scaffolding around the statue. Video ends with various images of poverty ridden neighborhoods and the individuals who live there; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:20:32; koppel_00084 (Box 3)
    - More Poor Housing/Exteriors of House of Republic/Roof Shots of Men Taking Down Flagpole/Roof Shots/Brief Interview with Chief Engineer of House of Republic (87) (Rupen No. B20), 03/06/1990; Exterior footage of poor housing in Bucharest. Exterior footage of the House of Republic and surrounding area. Construction workers taking down a flagpole. Rooftop shots of Bucharest. Brief interview with the Chief Engineer involved in building the House of Republic [in English] Interview focuses on the physical characteristics of the building as well as the engineer's insight into its construction; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:21:17; koppel_00085 (Box 3)
    - Timisoara Still Photos with Moves (88), 03/12/1990; Black and white still photos of individuals and their families. Black and white still photos of Timișoara during the Romanian Revolution; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:12:35; koppel_00086 (Box 7)
    - Lenin Statue: Wrecking Ball (89), circa 03/1990; Footage of Lenin statue removal operation in Bucharest after the Romanian Revolution of 1989. Associated program: Death of a Dictator; Videotape, Video8, original footage, 2:00:00; koppel_00087 (Box 76)
    - Audio Casette Transfers Side B (90), circa 03/1991; Videotape, Betacam SP, submaster, 0:30:00; koppel_00088 (Box 3)
    - Audio Casette Transfers Side A (Chanting, Singing) (91), 03/18/1990; Videotape, Betacam SP, submaster, 0:30:00; koppel_00089 (Box 3)
    - Koppel Report Open: V/O "Big Daddy" (from Opus) (92), 03/17/1990; Videotape, Betacam, master, 0:05:00; koppel_00090 (Box 3)
    - Act 2 Translations (93), circa 03/1990; Videotape, Betacam SP, master, 0:05:00; koppel_00091 (Box 3)
    - Original Music: 13 Cues (7:00 approx), 2TRK Stereo Master (94)., 03/26/1990; Audio tape, 1/4 inch audio tape, master, 0:10:00; koppel_00092 (Box 76)
    - Music for Segment 1 Opening (:13) (95), circa 03/1990; Audio tape, 1/4 inch audio tape, master, 0:10:00; koppel_00093 (Box 76)
    - Segments 1 and 2 (96), 03/22/1990; Audio tape, 1/4 inch audio tape, master, 0:10:00; koppel_00094 (Box 76)
    - Attention L. Chapman, Washington Transport Desk (blank tape?) (97)., circa 03/1990; Audio tape, 1/4 inch audio tape, master, 0:10:00; koppel_00095 (Box 76)
    - Clip Reel 1: Romania Dec. 22nd (CR1), 12/22/1989; Romania December 22 clip reel. Speeches at outdoor rally (night). Footage from inside television station, including statements by Sergiu Nicolaescu and Mircea Dinescu. Speech at outdoor rally (day). Speeches at outdoor rally from top of truck (patriotic music overlay). Major Lupoi statement at television station. Various statements at television station. Large demonstrations in the streets and Revolution Square. Protesters throwing books from balcony of central committee building. Crowds singing and chanting. Statement by Petre Roman [in Romanian]; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:25:09; koppel_00096 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 2 (CR2) (2c), 12/22/1989; Romanian television broadcasts. Clip reel includes political statements broadcast on Romanian television; performance of patriotic choral music; CFSN members appeals for a cease fire; scenes of crowds outside television station; statement by Ion Iliescu [in Romanian]; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:43:47; koppel_00097 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 3: TVR: Balcony/TV Studio (CR3) (3c), 12/22/1989; Various statements from Romanian television studio alternate with speeches from balcony [in Romanian] TVR footage; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:49:19; koppel_00098 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 4: TVR: Celebrations in Timisoara/Night Rally in Bucharest (CR4) (4c), 12/22/1989; Street violence at night. Public demonstrations. Crowds chanting. Various speeches from balcony. Statement by Emil Dumitrescu on Romanian television [in Romanian] TVR footage; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:23:56; koppel_00099 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 5: TVR: TV Studio at Night/Demo in Square/Nico Ceaucescu Capture (CR5) (5c), 12/22/1989; Various statements from Romanian television studio, including statements read by Teodor Brates, George Marinescu, and others [in Romanian] Night scenes of Bucharest demonstrations. Footage of Nicu Ceausescu capture. TVR footage; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:44:53; koppel_00100 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 6: TVR (CR6) (6c), 12/22/1989; TVR broadcast including statement by Ion Iliescu [in Romanian]; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:06:35; koppel_00101 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 7: Romania (CR7) (7c), 12/23/1989; Night rally in Bucharest. Daytime fighting. Romanian television broadcast. Dan Marin with bloodied face in studio accused of crimes against Romanian people. Various political statements delivered on Romanian television, including appearences by Ion Iliescu and Petre Roman [Romanian with English translation]; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:48; koppel_00102 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 8: Romania (CR8) (8c), 12/23/1989; Night fighting. Night rally. Romanian television broadcast. Day fighting. Transport of wounded. Securitate arrested. Ion Iliescu statement on Romanian television. Night fighting with buildings on fire. Various statements broadcast on Romanian television [Romanian with English translation]; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:54:30; koppel_00103 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 9: Airport/TVR Studio/Airport (CR9) (9c), 12/23/1989-12/24/1989; Daytime fighting at airport. Bus attacked. Arrests at airport. Daytime celebrations. Romanian television newscast. More airport arrests. Crowd chanting. Airport fighting, tanks, fighter jets. Airport interiors. Interview about fighting at airport and bus attack; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:57:42; koppel_00104 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 10 (CR10) (10c), 12/24/1989; Dan Marin on television at airport. Removal of wounded at airport. People watching news on airport television. Fighter jets circle airport, airport fighting. Vehicle inspections, soldiers on patrol in armored vehicles and tanks. Securitate arrests. Bodies pulled from graves. Street fighting. Balcony speeches and crowds chanting. Fighting at airport. Romanian television broadcast showing still photos from the revolution. Street scenes. Cathedral and street memorials; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:52:47; koppel_00105 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 11 (CR11) (11c), 12/25/1989; Soldiers cleaning debris from streets. Defaced Ceausescu portrait. Street fighting and buildings on fire. Ceausescu books and pamphlets burned in the streets. Street scenes. Romanian television broadcast; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:59:12; koppel_00106 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 12 (CR12) (12c), 12/26/1989; Soldiers patrolling the streets of Bucharest. Scenes of street fighting with soldiers and civilian fighters. Speeches from balcony. Dead Ceausescu. Crowds in Revolution Square. Digging graves and burying the dead. Graveyard memorials and street memorials. Checkpoint searches. Marching crowd and demonstrations; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:54:49; koppel_00107 (Box 7)
    - Clip Reel 14 (CR14) (14c), 12/26/1989-12/29/1989; Clips from international news coverage of the Romanian revolution. Crowds in Revolution Square. Street fighting. Soldiers patrolling streets. Street memorials. Dead Ceausescu and Ceausescu trial. Ion Iliescu and Petre Roman press conference. Soldiers outside Romanian television in Bucharest. Clips from Romanian television broadcasts. Scenes inside Interior Ministry facilities. Winter street scenes, tanks in snow. Interview with Corneliu Bogdan [in English] Scenes from inside Ceausescu's Snagov palace. Scenes inside Interior Ministry, including secret files; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:51:35; koppel_00108 (Box 8)
    - Clip Reel 15/Pollution/Factories (CR15), 01/01/1990-01/07/1990; Clips from international news coverage of the Romanian revolution including interviews and speeches. Crowded Romanian market. Memorial services. Short cartoon of pigs wearing tuxedos. Marching crowds and demonstrations. Footage of fighting in Revolution Square. Pollution from factories. General news coverage including sports, airplane crashes, and fighting near Baku.; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:59:21; koppel_00109 (Box 8)
    - Clip Reel 16 (CR16) (16c), 12/19/1989-01/08/1990; File footage of Ceausescu speeches. Footage of pastor Laszlo Tokes and wife Edit Tokes at home and at church in Timisoara. Interview with Laszlo Tokes [in English] Statement by Laszlo Tokes [in Hungarian] Clips from international news coverage of the Romanian revolution including marching crowds and demonstrations. Romanian television broadcasts; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:50:30; koppel_00110 (Box 8)
    - Romania: Complete Dub (16c), 02/19/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00111 (Box 8)
    - Romanian Revolution Street Fighting/Last Politburo Meeting with Ceausescu (17c), 12/22/1989-12/24/1989; Civilian demonstrations. Revolutionaries have taken over Romanian T.V. station. Multiple clips of street fighting including tanks and fire fights. Civilians distributing food to soldiers. Hospital footage of individuals injured during the fighting. Last Politburo meeting with Ceausescu; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:04:20; koppel_00112 (Box 8)
    - Panorama: Romania: Conversation, 01/08/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00113 (Box 8)
    - Nicolae Ceausescu's Last Speech/Petre Interview/Mag Interview (18c)., circa 03/1990; Clips from Nicolae Ceausescu's last speech at the Palace of the Parliament. Footage of Revolution Square after Ceausescu's speech including his helicopter departure. Interview with a man named Petre [Questions in English, answers in Romanian] Interview pertained to what life was like in Romania 15 years ago and what life was like after the revolution. Interview with a woman named Mag [Questions in English, answers in Romanian] Interview pertaining to what life was like as a woman in Romania, including questions related to contraception; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:35:51; koppel_00114 (Box 8)
    - ABC Bucharest Files/Nicolae Ceausescu's Last Speech (20c), 12/21/1989-12/22/1989; Footage of bloody individual being led through the streets by a crowd of people. Multiple scenes of street fighting. Nicolae Ceausescu's last speech at the Palace of the Parliament. Footage includes multiple angles of the speech as well as the helicopter departure and the aftermath in Revolution Square; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:34:18; koppel_00115 (Box 8)
    - Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu's Trial/Execution Aftermath (21c)., circa 03/1990; Nicolae Ceausescu being escorted from a tank. Trial of Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu. Footage and images of the Ceausescus after their execution by firing squad; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:54:18; koppel_00116 (Box 8)
    - ABC Romania Clips/Revolution Aftermath B-roll (22c), 02/09/1990; Press conference regarding the transitional government in Romania [in Romanian and English] Conference addresses the involvement of Communist Party members in the new government as well as issues surrounding free speech. Street memorials. Interior footage of a destroyed building. Multiple scenes of individuals walking the streets of Bucharest. Footage of individuals replacing windows. Armed soldiers searching a building with unarmed civilians. Vehicle check points. TVR broadcast footage. Clip of a black and white movie in English.; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:34:13; koppel_00117 (Box 8)
    - Timosoara Demonstrations/Statements of Individuals that were a Part of the Demonstrations (23c), 12/22/1989; Large demonstration in Timosoara. Street memorials. Several individuals making statements into a camera. Dialogue between army officer and civilians. Footage of meeting [in Romanian] Interviews and statements made by a variety of individuals during and after the Timosoara demonstrations. Street fighting (night). Interview with several handcuffed individuals. Street fighting (day). Brief segment from TVR; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:56:46; koppel_00118 (Box 8)
    - Romanian Revolution Demonstrations/Street Fighting/Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu's Trial (24c), 12/22/1989; Couple being searched and held at gun point by soldier. Home footage of Romanian streets during the revolution with commentary by the individual operating the camera [in Romanian] Press conference with military officer. Footage of Romanian demonstrations with commentary. TVR footage. Street fighting (night). Burning building. Mass graves. Trial of Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 1:04:20; koppel_00119 (Box 8)
    - Romanian TV Clip Reel 1: Dub of Clip Reel Compiled by ABC Bucharest (25c), 12/22/1989; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00120 (Box 8)
    - Romanian TV Clip Reel 2 (26c), 12/23/1989-12/24/1989; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00121 (Box 9)
    - Romanian TV Clip Reel 3A (27c), 12/25/1989; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00122 (Box 9)
    - Romanian TV Clip Reel 3B (28c), circa 12/1989; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00123 (Box 9)
    - Romanian TV Clip Reel 4A/Plus Sahia Films Clip Reel (29c), circa 12/1989; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00124 (Box 9)
    - London File Footage/Ceausescu History (30c), circa 03/1990; Black and white footage of an early Nicolae Ceausescu speech. Ceausescu receiving medal in England. Ceausescu meeting with a variety of world leaders including Anwar Sadat, Mikhail Gorbachev, and several Iranian leaders. Journalist segment with interview [in Romanian] Interview with individual explaining why Ceausescu used faked photos in publications; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:22:52; koppel_00125 (Box 9)
    - ABC Bucharest Romania (31c), 12/19/1989; Videotape, Betacam SP, dub, 0:20:00; koppel_00126 (Box 9)
    - ABC Buchrest/Filed Cass. Dub from ABC and ITN (32c), 02/08/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:30:00; koppel_00127 (Box 9)
    - ABC News Bucharest: Clip Reel 3 (33c), 02/09/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:30:00; koppel_00128 (Box 9)
    - Ceausescu File Footage (No. 34C) (34c), circa 02/1990; Ceausescu File Footage. Scenes of Ceausescu delivering speeches, meeting with diplomats, and posing for photo ops. Ceausescu meeting with a United States diplomat. Soldiers marching in parade. Footage of empty Romanian grocery stores. Footage of Romanian factories.; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:28:38; koppel_00129 (Box 9)
    - Romanian City Life/Ceausescu File Footage (No. 35C) (35c), circa 02/1990; Children visiting a Romanian museum filled with Ceausescu propaganda. Footage of Romanian city in rubble. Crowded streets and busses. Factories and heavy industry. Ceausescu File Footage. Scenes of Ceausescu delivering speeches, meeting with diplomats, and posing for photo ops. Ceausescu meeting with Yasser Arafat. Segment about Romania narrated in German; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:19:36; koppel_00130 (Box 9)
    - Romania Clip Reel (36c), 03/05/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 1:00:00; koppel_00131 (Box 9)
    - Zoe Ceaucescu Dragged into TV Station/Timisoara Mass Graves/Crowds in Front of Timosoara Opera House (37c), 03/08/1990; Streets of Bucharest after the Revolution. Zoe Ceaucescu being dragged into a TV station. Timisoara mass graves. Graves include images of burned and disfigured bodies. Large crowd assembled in front of Timosoara opera house. A speech is being delivered to the crowd; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:22:52; koppel_00132 (Box 3)
    - Iasi Demonstrations/Books Thrown out of Windows/Dead Bodies on the Street//Nicolae Ceausescu Villa at the Seaside Resort of Neptun (38c)., 03/08/1990; Demonstrations and crowds marching. Books burning in the street. Books being thrown out of windows. Images of dead bodies. Footage of hospital and injured patients. Exterior footage of Ceausescu's villa in Neptun. Interior footage of Ceausescu's villa in Neptun; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:22:35; koppel_00133 (Box 3)
    - Brasov Demonstrations/Street Fighting (39c), 03/08/1990; Demonstrations and crowds marching. Large crowd assembling outside of a building (multiple angles and vantage points). Street fighting; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 0:22:08; koppel_00134 (Box 3)
    - ABC Bucharest Tape/Interiors of House of Republic/Interviews with Soldiers/Exteriors of House of Republic (19c), circa 02/1990; Press conference in Romanian. Interior footage of the House of the Republic (multiple angles and vantage points). Brief interview with soldier regarding the construction of the House of the Republic. Balcony shots. Brief interview with soldier regarding Ceausescu's use of the House of the Republic as well as the building itself. Exterior footage of the House of the Republic; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 0:18:17; koppel_00135 (Box 3)
    - Ceausescu at Home Part 1 (AA), circa 12/1989; Footage of the Ceausescus doing a variety of activities with music in the background. Activities include hosting parties, walking in snowy streets, talking with farmers, hunting, boating, receiving awards, playing with children, and greeting enthusiastic citizens. Aerial footage of Romanian countryside. Footage of various bodies of water; Videotape, Betacam, original footage, 1:21:44; koppel_00274 (Box 9)